

# Patrick O'Brien

Web Developer

#### **Contact**

**Address** 08001, Barcelona Spain

**Phone** 633272260

**E-mail** obrienp2321@gmail.com

**WWW** patrickobrien.onrender.com

#### Skills

User Experience Design Version Control Systems: Git, Github Front-End Programming: HTML5, CSS3, React Back-End Programming: Node.js, MongoDB, Express Design Software: Photoshop, Figma CRM and Microsoft Dynamics, 3W

## Languages

English

Advanced

Spanish

Upper intermediate

A recent graduate of NuCamp Full Stack Web and Mobile Development Bootcamp and a self-taught developer with valuable training and hands-on experience in front-end and back-end technologies. Possesses a background in Business Administration, experience in customer service, sales, and teaching, and a passion for web development, demonstrating confidence in the ability to excel as a junior front end web developer.

## **Professional Experience**

2023-01 -Current

### **Freelance Web Developer**

HP Online Store, Barcelona

- Developed and implemented MERN application called the HP Notepad, which is currently used by WebHelp Spain as a tool to create dynamic email templates on the fly
- Created various tools within the HP Notepad to track shipments, calculate VAT, and provide a daily dashboard section that pulls from various APIs using a nodecron job to gather horoscope, weather, and news data every morning
- Collaborated with colleagues to gather requirements, provide regular updates, and ensure the application remained functional and efficient

2021-01 -Current

## **Customer Service & Sales Representative**

HP Online Store, Barcelona

- Handle inbound phone, chat, and email post-sales service requests for orders placed on the HP Store, UK Market
- Coordinate between the warehouse, security team, and finance team to ensure deliveries, returns, and refunds are sent according to SLA
- Manage CRM software and other internal communication tools

2017-06 -2021-01

# **Support Agent**

Match.com, Barcelona

 Assist customers in site navigation, manage subscriptions, payments, and refunds, troubleshoot site issues. Investigate fraud, coordinate with Safety Team

2016-09 -2019-01

#### **Private English Tutor**

Kids&Us, Barcelona

 Customized classes to individual students needs in a variety of topics, largely conversation based

2014-06 -2016-09

#### **Restaurant Manager**

Mi Madre's Restaurant, Austin, Texas

- Delegated opening, closing duties, maintained daily operations of restaurant
- In charge of training new employees, training material, one to one feedback
- Organized company wide training of Point of Sales operating system, in English and Spanish

#### **Education**

2022-01 - Certificate of Completion: Web Development
2023-06
2008-08 - Bachelor of Science: Business Administration
University of Connecticut - Storrs, CT USA